Guide to the Philippines miscellany, 1965-2001.
Philippines miscellany
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Philippines miscellany, 1965-2001.
6505
H. Soewoto
4 cubic ft.
Printed materials, newspaper clippings, posters, and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Political publications, brochures, posters, banners, handbills and other ephemera relating to national and local elections.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Political publications, brochures, posters, banners, handbills and other ephemera relating to national and local elections of 8 May 1995 and 14 May 2001. Official publications relating to various government programs; family planning, National Reconciliation and Development Program, land reform, U.S.A.-Philippine relations, and tourism. Transcripts of speeches given by President Ferdinand E. Marcos and Imelda Romualdez Marcos at the 19th General Conference of the International Union for the Scientific Study of Population, Manila, 1981. Presidential Decree Nos. 316 (1973), 815 (1975) and 816.
In addition the collection includes educational and promotional materials relating to the 2004 election in the Philippines. The first part consist of materials that provide a better understanding of the 2004 Philippine Synchronized Election. These materials were produced by organizations such as NAMFREL and COMELEC and included both instructions concerning the election process as well as lists of candidates. Samples of pre-election surveys and a bundle of newspaper clippings from the “Philippine Daily Inquirer” concerning the election are also included.
There are also promotional materials for the presidential and senatorial and local candidates such as smear pamphlets, comics, stickers, posters, cards, calendars, banners and sample ballots. The candidates represented are Fernando Poe Jr. (FJP) and his vice presidential candidate Loren Legarda, Gloria Macapagal Arroyo and her vice president candidate Noli de Castro, Raul Roco and his vice president partner Hermie Aquino, presidential candidate Ping Lacson and presidential candidate Bro Eddie. Senatorial candidates included are Manuel Roxas, Salvador Escudero, Rodolfo Biazon, Alfred Lim, Boots Anson-Roa, Carlos Padilla, Juan Ponce Enrile, Ernesto Maceda, Dr. Parouk Hussin, Ernesto Herrera, Jinggoy Estrada, Robert Barbers, Roman Revilla, Richard Gordon, Aquilino Pimentel, Pia Cayeteno, Jamby Madrigal, Miriam Defensor Santiago, Francisco Cahvez, Didagen Dilangalen, Francisco Tatad, Robert Jaworski and John Henry Osmeña. Parties represented in this collection are Forward Taguig, the Performance Team, Batang Makati Movement, Lakas-CMD, Dodot Henry Lito (DHL), Lakas ng Batangas. Geographical areas included are Makati, Taguig, Quezon, Navotas, Pasay
SUBJECTS
Names:
Marcos, Ferdinand E. (Ferdinand Edralin), 1917-; Marcos, Ferdinand E. (Ferdinand Edralin), 1917-; Marcos, Imelda Romualdez, 1929-; Marcos, Imelda Romualdez, 1929-
Subjects:
Elections -- Philippines.; Political parties -- Philippines.; Elections; Political parties; Political science
Places:
Philippines -- Politics and government -- 1976-; Philippines
INFORMATION FOR USERS
An item level list of contents of box 1 can be found in the accession folder.
CONTAINER LIST
- Election Materials 1995-2001
  - See list in accession folder (Box 1)
- Election Materials 2004
  - Pamphlets and Small Campaign Material
    - Taskforce Kilatis, 2004; 1 Flyer, 1 poster, 1 leaflet (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mindanao Coalition of Development NGO Networks, 2004; 1 Leaflet (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - COMELEC Voter Information Sheet, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Pamphlet, Commission on Elections, Voter Information Sheet, List of Candidates and sample ballot
    - NAMFREL volunteer ID, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Volunteer ID card
    - Candidates Forum, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Paper, Parish Pastoral Council For Responsible Voting & COMELEC
    - COMELEC List of Registered/Accredited Political Parties, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bakit si FPJ ang dapat iboto?, 2004; 1 Leaflet (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - COMELEC General instructions for election inspectors, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Pamphlet, General instructions for the board of election inspectors on the casting and counting of votes
    - Social Weather Station Pre-Election survey 2004, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      March and April edition, publishing dates 5 and 23 April 2004
    - Patnubay sa Halalan 2004 (MGA Plataparma de Gobyerno Ng MGA Kandidato SA Pagkapangulo), 2004; 1 Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - COMELEC General instructions for government, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Pamphlet, General instructions for municipal/city/provincial and district boards
    - Presidential Campaigns in Post-1986 Philippines, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Paper by Julio C. Teehankee Ph.D. De La Salle University
    - Pulse Asia's national survey on 2004 elections, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Paper
    - Manimala Ka - Reporter Magazine, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Magazine
    - Smear concerning Gloria Macapagal, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Leaflets
    - Political comics concerning Gloria's "Tungo Sa Matag Na Republika", smear on FJP, and Laban ng Demokratikong Pilipino by Ping Lacson, 2004; 3 Comics (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Priorities Philippines "A turning point in the first 360 days", 2000; Print-out (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Promotional material Ping Lacson, 2004; 4 pamphlets, 4 stickers, 1 calendar (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Promotional material FJP and Loren Legarda, 2004; 3 pamphlets, 6 sample ballots, 1 card, 1 calendar, 3 stickers, 2 booklets (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Promotional material Gloria Arrayo and Noli de Castro, 2004; 6 sample ballots, 1 booklet, 1 calendar, 2 stickers, 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Promotional material Raul Roco and Hermie Aquino, 2004; 2 pamphlets, 1 calendar (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Promotional material Bro Eddie, 2004; 3 pamphlets, 1 sample ballot (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Coop Natcco Party, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Isang Bansa Isang Diwa, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Abanse Pinay Party, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - AVE Party, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bayan Muna Party, 2004; 2 pamphlets, 1 sticker, 1 sample ballot (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - PM Partido ng Manggagawa, 2004; 2 pamphlets, 1 sample ballot (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - PMAP People's Movement Against Poverty, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Gabriela Women's Party List, 2004; 4 pamphlets, 1 sticker, 1 sample ballot (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Akbayan Party, 2004; 4 pamphlets, 1 sticker, 1 sample ballot, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Aksa Aksyon Sambayanan Party, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Anakpawis Party, 2004; 3 pamphlets, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - AASJS, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 ruler (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bigkis Pinoy Party, 2004; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Abaypamilya Partlist, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Philippine Daily Inquirer, issues Vol. 19 no. 115 - 152, 2004; Newspaper (Box 2)
    - COMELEC Information kit for the May 10, 2004 synchronized national and local elections, 2004; Kit (Box 2)
    - Kim Atienza and Lito Atienza, Cita Astals, 2004; 3 pamphlets, 2 stickers, 1 calendar (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Performance Team: Baby Ramos Pangilinan, Divine Jacome, Pasia, Tolentino Jr. and Isreal Cruzado, 2004; 8 pamphlets, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Vote for Councilor: Peralta, Astals, CalinginDaba, Advincula, Benaldo, Guia, Cabanlas, Jongko, 2004; 7 pamphlets, 1 stickers, 2 cards (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Vote for Mayor/ Vice- Mayor: Tamondong, Belmonte / Alcera and Bagatsing, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 cartoon, 1 card, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 1st District Navotas: Ramirez, Cruz, Peña, Plamenco, 2004; 4 pamphlet, 3 stickers (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 2nd District Navotas: Santos, Gino-Gino, Patis, Boyet Mendez Chu, Lizan, 2004; 3 pamphlets, 4 stickers (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 2nd District Taguig: Reyes, Tinga, Bartolome and Minglana, 2004; 4 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 1st District Makati: Tolentino, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 2nd District Makati: Paraan, Torrente, Tercero, Maccay, Lapasaran, Yabut, Ibay, 2004; 8 pamphlets, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - 1st District Davao: Lavina, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - 2nd Distric Parañaque: Manny de Guia and Lakas-CMD Bert Bonsol, 2004; 2 pamphlets, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - 5th District Manila: Hizon, Cuna and Ocampo, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 2 cards (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - 4th District Q.C.: Bong Suntay, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Arman Sanchez and Dondon Dimacuha, 2004; 2 cards, 4 stickers (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Candidates Padayon Pilipino - Lakas - CMD, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Mel Mathay, 2004; 2 stickers (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Nani Perez, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Eddie B. Dimacuha, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Gody C. Valera, 2004; 2 pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Toby Tiangco for Mayor, FPJ for President, 2004; 2 pamphlets, 2 stickers, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Gardy Cruz, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Riolo Golez: Support Gloria for President, 2004; 1 leaflet, 1 calendar (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Butz Aquino, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Candidates KNP PDP - Laban, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Dodot Henry Lito (DHL): Henry Lanot, 2004; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - District 1 Pasay City: Tonya Cuneta, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Maning Ravanera, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Ian Enerio Acenas, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Ian Mark Quiblat Nacaya, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Sandiwa, 2004; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Shalom Lorenzana, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Tinnex Jaraula, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Angging Librado, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dodot Jaworski, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Juan Sia, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Miriam Defensor Santiago, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 sticker, 1 fan (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Jinggoy Estrada, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 card, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Boots Anson-Roa, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Doc Hussin: Peacemaker, 2004; 1 sticker, 1 fan, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Pimentel, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Mar Roxas, 2004; 1 fan, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Osmeña Ibalik, 2004; 1 sticker, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Ramon Bong Revilla Jr., 2004; 1 fan, 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Juan Ponce Enrile, 2004; 1 sticker, 1 calendar, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Salvador Escudero, 2004; 1 pamphlet, 1 card, 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Biazon, 2004; 1 sticker, 1 card (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Bobby Barbers, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Wow Dick Gordon, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Maceda, 2004; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Padilla, 2004; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Jamby Madrigal, 2004; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - KIT Tatad, 2004; 1 calendar (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Katapat Fred Lim, 2004; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Compañera Pia Cayetano, 2004; 1 pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Button Elias Viray, 2004; MU-1682 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Posters and Banners
    - Ehem! Anti-Corruption Movement, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - NAMFREL, Davao City, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Office of the President "Stop terrorism", 2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - FPJ (Fernando Poe Jr.) For President, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Loren Legarda - Vice President Candidate Poster, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Gloria Macapagal Arroyo for President Posters, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Ping Lacson for President, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bro. Eddie Villanueva for President, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - FPJ For President and Loren Learda as Vice President, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Coop Natcco Party, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - PM Partido ng Manggagawa, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Gabriela Women's Party List, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Anakpawis Party, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Partido Navoteño, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bayan Muna Party, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Akbayan Party, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lakas CMD, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Liberal Party: Dimacuha, Sanchez, Mandanas, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Partido Navoteño: Santos, Tiangco, Cruz, Boyet Mendez Chu, Ramirez, Lagman, Plamenco, Gino-Gino, Santiago, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Sigan ng Bayan: Iba Naman!, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Rody Duterte, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Parañaque City: Rico Golez, Beng Amurao, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Vote for Councilor: Sotto, Minglana, King Yabut, Marquez, Dguia, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Misc: Chipeco for Congressman and Bistex for Vice-Mayor, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Isang Bansa Isang Diwa, 2004 (Folder 2)
    - Aksa Aksyon Sambayanan Party, 2004 (Folder 3)
    - Jamby Madrigal, 2004 (Folder 4)
    - Mar Tokas, 2004 (Folder 5)
    - WOW Dick Gordon, 2004 (Folder 6)
    - Miriam Defensor Santiago, 2004 (Folder 7)
    - Maceda, 2004 (Folder 8)
    - Enrile, 2004 (Folder 9)
    - Jamby Madrigal for Senador, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cayetano for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Escudero for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Enrile for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Revilla for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Miriam Defensor Santiago for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Mar Roxas for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Biazon for Senator, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)